Ezequiel Andrüsh

Sr SysAdmin / Ssr DevOps / Ssr SRE

<u>About me</u>: I am an IT professional passionate about learning and solving technical problems. I consider myself a friendly and good tempered person, open to ask or give help to my teammates. I am good at quick learning new technologies in order to improve my performance immediately. I like to work as a part of a bigger team and interact with others.

At the time of writing this document I am studying Real-Time Applications with integrated data acquisition with single board computers (SBC) and real time operating systems.

I consider myself as an IT Geek, I love experimenting with Arduino, Raspberry Pi's and all that kind of stuff. If it blinks, I want to know how it works.

In order to reduce my stress, I like to practice sports as swimming and water polo. I also practice traditional archery. I like both teamwork and introspective sports.

About my career: I am an old school Unix/Linux SysAdmin that evolved to a DevOps/SRE Engineer. I have more than 20 years of experience working with on-premise/Virtualized Linux systems in a wide variety of scenarios.

I also worked with containers in GCP using the GKE platform and docker on laaS virtualized servers as a middleground to help applications teams to "containerize" their app in order to make the big jump to Kubernetes.

Achievements

Linux Containers Standardization: Standardization of docker installs on Linux Servers inside Company Internal Operations. This included define the standard with Management and implement the solution through scripts and automation.

Container Images Standardization: Define implement and update Standard container base images for consumption inside Company Internal Operations. Delivery to the Container Registry via CI/CD pipelines.

Create a Datacenter from scratch: Define with management, implement and build a datacenter from scratch.

From buying the hardware, racks and network hardware to install and deploy all the services needed for Smart Bridge SRL operations in La Plata harbor.

Education

UTN - La Plata

Systems Analyst – Completed (2011)

Systems Engineering – Incomplete

ACCENTURE ACADEMY – Buenos Aires

Agile Foundations - 2018

DevOps Fundamentals - 2018

Linux Containers - 2018

Kubernetes: A practical approach - 2019 Introduction to Design Thinking - 2019

Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Advanced (written and spoken)

Skills

Linux

Docker

Kubernetes

********** *****

Ansible

Terraform Python

Git

Work History

PROPIFY – Remote

January 2023 - December 2024

IoT Engineer: As an IoT engineer I was responsible of the zwave Gateway on the SmartHome platform, this includes:

- Define, execute and monitor StamtHome OTA updates procedures.
- Provide support to clients.
- Research and evaluate alternatives, improvements and enhancements for the new gateway iteration (version 3 zwave gateway)

SRE Engineer: As the platform SRE engineer I was responsible of the following items:

- Design and implement the infrastructure needed in AWS to provide OTA packages CI/CD and determine what, how and when provide automations to the procedure.
- Oversee the platform and take preventive and corrective actions accordingly.

SOUTH GEEKS – Remote

2020-2021

NOC Engineer: As a NOC engineer working for a high profile IT security client I was responsible of the following tasks:

- Monitor all the SaaS environments running on GCP instances and act proactively when needed (more than 200 environments).
- Execute the product update procedures planned on my shift hours.
- On-Call duties. Root Cause analysis and incident response within complying SLA.

ACCENTURE – La Plata/C.A.B.A.

2018-2020

DevOps Engineer: As a DevOps Engineer working on Company Internal Operations my tasks were mainly focused on giving support to Internal Application teams and defining standards in order to maintain homogeneous deployments for better maintenance.

- Level 3 support engineer for Linux Servers troubleshooting.
- Docker deployment standardization for Linux laaS Servers. Defining the standard with management and automate the new installs using scripts on bash. Also In one year all the existing deployments prior to the standard definition were fixed. At the time of my leaving there were about 300 servers running docker.
- VMWare Administrator for a non-productive datacenter located in Chicago.
- Writing terraform code for the IaC GKE module and support application teams on their migration way to microservices architecture.
- Analyze and provide automation to maintenance tasks over the laaS and PaaS environments.

WATER RESOURCE AUTHORITY – La Plata

IT Consultant (2016-2018): As an IT Consultant working for an internal project I had the following responsibilities:

- Define the Data Network for Data Acquisition of Weather Stations installed for an Early Alert and Monitoring system
- Execute field checks on sensors and data loggers in more than 40 different locations on Buenos Aires Province territory (this sensors checked Water Levels, atmospheric pressure, rain, air humidity and wind).
- Hardware and software requirements analysis for mounting a data-center to support the infrastructure described above.
- Admin tasks for Internal Ticketing System administration for creating cases to P3 users (those were from other public services locations) implemented with GLPI.

SysAdmin (1998-2016): Technical support for 12 workstations with Windows 2000/XP. Firewalls and servers administration when Sr. Sysadmin went on vacation or sick leave.

• L1 support for end users, antivirus and maintenance tasks.

SMART BRIDGE S.R.L – La Plata/Berisso/Ensenada 2009-2016

IT MAnager: This was a small company (less than 10 employees) on logistics business. I created the IT department with 2 people from scratch. The tasks involved where:

- Define the needs, problems and budget with management.
- Submit a draft for the solution and validate with management.
- Buy all the hardware needed and install all the infrastructure (racks, network cables, firewalls, switches, servers, etc) on site.
- Virtualization of the servers using XEN when needed, install linux workstations, firewall using IPTables, backup server (Bacula), OpenVPN server and endpoints to integrate PtP network in all the three locations and notebooks on the road.
- Install and maintain a biometrics time & attendance control system and security systems with IP cameras.

PUBLIC JUSTICE SECTOR

La Plata/Mercedes/Bahía Blanca/Dolores/Mar del Plata 2002

Teacher: Creator of content and instructor of training courses for using GNU/Linux servers and workstations in Buenos Aires Public Administration.

Course content was: IPTables, Firewalls (design and implementation), Server configuration and administration, webservers (Apache), email servers (Exim), DHCP, NFS and Samba. Monitor all the SaaS environments running on GCP instances and act proactively when needed (more than 200 environments).

OCCAM SA - La Plata

2000 - 2002

SysAdmin:

- Configuration, deploy, maintenance and administration in 3 GNU/Linux servers (Mandrake, RedHat and Debian distros)
- Administration of Fileservers (NFS, SMB), Email Servers (Exim), Webservers (Apache)
- Mainteinance for SCO/Unix server as database server (Informix) using telephone answering machine software via modem.

Contact Info: www.zekeand.com.ar +54 9 221 675 8380 ezequielandrush@gmail.com /in/carlos-ezequiel-andrush/ @andrushezequiel